Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
"Great Detective Conan"
"Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi"
Whaa! Ouch!
Oh no, it's gotten even more painful.
Say, if we go on like this,
will we be electrocuted?
I see...
It's easy to figure out with this hint.
Eh?
That case where you made
that spectacular fuss.
"September 30th, 2010"
"Next stop, Beika 3-Chome,
next stop is Beika 3-Chome."
"Bus Stop
Beika 3-Chome"
Hmm... this is cute.
Ah, Shin'ichi, isn't this cute?
- Umm...
- Cute, isn't it?
Kyaa!
Hey!
What's up?
"Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend
Mori Ran"
A mo... mo... molester!
That guy's a molester!
Eh?!
"High School Student Detective
Kudo Shin'ichi"
Hey, someone! Please catch that person!
Wait!
He's running away! Wait!
Ran, wait up!
Eh?
Where did he go?
He's gone.
He disappeared...
Shin'ichi, over here!
Wait, you rascal!
So persistent!
Wait, I said!
Wait!
Hold up, you molester!
Ala?
He's disappeared again.
Ah, he's there!
You...
Wait!
That molester knows his way
around here too well!
Ran! Drive him to your left!
- Eh?!
- Leave this to me.
Yes!
Ah!
Wait!
Give it up. There's no escape.
I just can't forgive someone for touching
a person's butt and then running away!
That's dangerous!
You should've known better, Molester-san!
Give up, you molester!
Because I'm the only one
who can touch Ran.
What did you say?!
No, nothing.
"Molester - Sawada Osamu"
I'm sorry. Please overlook it this once.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Doesn't look like anything's broken, Mister.
Ah, excuse me, here too?
This is a burn, isn't it?
Count himself lucky; he got off easy.
Point is, you're being too soft on him!
Now, let's go to the police. Got that?
Ah, I'm sorry!
I won't touch you anymore!
No good! I definitely won't forgive you.
Please give me a break and not the police.
Give it up. She's a bad person.
Shin'ichi!
Let's go!
Get going!
Roger.
Now! Get walking!
Ah, excuse me, Policeman-san!
Miyano-san. Hang in there!
We'll take you to the hospital right away!
You're Yamashita-san, aren't you?
"MPD Investigation Unit One
Sato Miwako"
I'll ask you to remain here.
What is it?! I haven't done anything.
I want to hear details of
the circumstances.
"MPD Investigation Unit One
Takagi Wataru"
Kudo-kun, Ran-san... what's going on?
This person's a molester!
Please arrest him.
Molester!? Come with me!
Ah, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It was on impulse...
Tell me.
Who did you molest?
Ah, this person.
You picked... the wrong one, didn't you?
Takagi! Do your job!
Detective Sato, do you have a case?
Kudo-kun.
Yeah, bit of a one.
This Helper, Yamoshita Makoto-san,
had gone out shopping...
...when the artificial respirator maintaining
Miyano Katsuyo-san's respiration suddenly stopped.
With that, Katsuyo-san went into
cardiopulmonary arrest...
...and she's being taken to
the hospital in an ambulance.
Her respirator stopped?
The circuit breaker had failed once before,
but even if this is a similar incident...
Are you saying I wanted to kill Miyano-san?
When her respirator stopped,
no one was in the room with her.
If it hadn't contacted the hospital with
an alarm, Katsuyo-san could have died.
In short, I can't deny the possibility
that someone prepared this as a murder.
Would it be okay if I
took a little look around?
I'm sorry.
It was... just so cute...
Even if it is cute...
Come in.
Touching my butt is a crime!
In criminal law,
this sort of thing is the worst...
...and, yeah, you could even spend
a year or whatever in prison.
Moreover, there's the shock it gives
to the women victims!
There've been cases where they can't even
ride buses or trains anymore, you know!
If I end up like that...
...it'll have been your fault!
Detective. Are you okay dealing with me
rather than that case over there?
Thank you.
Since the person himself seems to regret it
and didn't do anything worse...
We'll have him write a letter of apology
at the police station.
Huh?
So half-assed!
I don't feel like giving up my complaint!
Excuse me.
Yes, this is Takagi.
Yes. Eh?
Sawada Osamu has a criminal record?!
Katsuyo-san was the victim of a traffic accident
several years ago while out walking.
After that she had a stroke.
Since her only immediate family, her daughter
Yukari-san, is too busy working to nurse her...
...they seem to have gotten Yamashita-san
as her Helper to care for her.
Recently she's been unconscious
and not even able to breathe for herself.
Even so, this artificial respirator
should have had a battery for emergencies.
So why isn't there a battery!?
The battery broke down and is being repaired.
What do you mean?
That could cause a
life-threatening problem, couldn't it?
Do you know what caused
the circuit breaker on it to fail?
I'm waiting for
the criminal investigation into that.
Even though I appear as a Helper...
...my salary is for being Miyano-san's nurse.
Why would you say I'd kill my own employer for?
I caught him sneaking into here.
While he was here, I bet he was peeping.
Anyhow, his criminal record
is for peeping, isn't it?
- Is that so, Sawada?
- My game isn't in peeping.
Then just what is your game?
That's...
And after that, where did he run off to?
Over here.
A security camera...
Why is that broken?
It seems Yukari-san was having her
underwear stolen, so she put that up...
...but she said it's been broken a long time now.
Ehh... So things like this are
the most recent style, huh...
These are pretty, too.
Hey, which ones would
high school students be interested in?
Eh... Wha... what would interest them...
Hey, wait. What are you doing
so suddenly, Kudo-kun?
No, it's not like that.
What sort of underwear
do you wear, Detective Sato?
Eh?!
Do you have lots of black ones?
Hmm... I do like black...
- Hey!
- Is that right.
Ran-chan! Do something about Kudo-kun!
I don't have time right now for Shin'ichi,
so if you would please.
This way.
Like I thought, do underwear thieves
prefer panties over bras?
Hmm, I guess so...
I wouldn't know such a thing!
Ask an underwear thief
directly yourself! Geez!
This is...
Mom...
Yukari-san!
Yukari-san, are you okay?
Where's Mom?
She was taken by ambulance
to the hospital a little while ago...
I'm sorry. If I had been back in time,
this wouldn't have happened.
"Katsuyo's daughter
Miyano Yukari"
Will she be saved?
I'm sure she will...
Anyhow, let's hurry to the hospital.
Excuse me.
I'm Sato of MPD Investigation Unit One.
You're Miyano Yukari-san, aren't you?
Has your underwear been stolen often?
Kudo-kun, what are you talking about?!
It often was before...
But not so much recently.
Kudo-kun, stay around here.
We'll be going to the hospital now.
After one more question.
How long has that security camera been broken?
6 months ago since the rains.
The camera seems to have short-circuited.
Was that linked to
the previous respirator incident?
If that was the cause before...
...is the camera the cause
this time around, too?
Put an end to this!
This is a matter of whether her mother
will live or die. What good does that do us!?
Ah, please wait!
I need a little of your time to hear
what you have to say.
Kudo-kun, you're being strange today.
That's true.
I may not seem to be me.
I understand the trick behind this case.
Still...
...who on earth is the criminal?
"Repeat Offender"
I guess this guy is a repeat offender.
That's right!
It was just like I thought.
But even so, Detective Takagi
didn't believe me at all!
At all? You apologize properly, too!
But I intend to live responsibly from here on.
You can't just rehabilitate like that
on your own!
I won't allow it!
Now, now Ran-chan, calm down.
Hey! Are you really repenting?
You haven't listened to a word
I've said since earlier!
That's not true...
Shin'ichi!
Say something!
Please take it out.
Huh?
The underwear you've stolen.
I guess it's no good if I don't bring them out?
Eh?! Underwear?
Like I thought, they are black.
Eh?
Black is best, isn't it?
Ah, well, black is the best...
Shin'ichi!
Do you always take black?
Well... I do love them.
Hey! Don't just exchange opinions
on stuff like that!
Fool! This is important.
You're saying the color of underwear
is what's important?
Well, that's...
Shin'ichi...
Shin'ichi, don't you feel even a little sorry
about me being molested?
No, it has nothing to do with that.
You aren't even the least bit
worried about me!
I am worried!
Don't cry over a thing like that!
You aren't nice!
- Eh?!
That's property damage!
Anyhow, I won't let you get away with this!
Yes, yes, yes.
Um... Can I borrow Sawada-san
for just a little while?
Go ahead, go ahead.
There's a lot of underwear being dried
around here, so why did you take this one?
Because I like black.
There is other underwear.
Hmm... I guess, how do I put it,
it's just about the color.
Ehh...
Do you know this woman?
How about it?
If you don't tell us,
you'll be charged with murder.
Mu... murder?!
Murder?!
Wait, lemme see that!
What is this about, Kudo-kun?
How about it, Sawada-san?
I know her.
I figured.
You've stolen from her before.
"Caught you at last, you rascal!
I'm calling the police!"
"I'm sorry. I'm sorry, it was just an impulse."
"I'm very sorry!"
"Do you like black?"
"The only ones that have
disappeared were black."
"I'm sorry."
"Do you have a girlfriend?"
"Yes."
"Then have her make or buy them for you."
"Don't go taking them anymore, got that?"
"Thank you very much."
"Wait, Yukari-san. This is..."
"Because you're here, we can let
various people off like this, can't we?"
"So it's okay, isn't it?"
"Thank you very much."
I don't believe you!
What are you gonna do, Detective Sato?
Well, everyone's different.
Different!?
Thank you very much.
Wait a minute, Kudo-kun.
What on earth is this about?
Sawada-san is a thief...
A repeat underwear thief.
Is he a murderer?
In some ways.
Oi, oi, oi, hang on there!
I don't understand what you mean.
Shin'ichi! Explain yourself properly!
Whichever it is,
you'll arrest Sawada-san, won't you?
That's true.
However, molesting and murder...
What's the difference?
Well...
Explain it to me properly.
Then, could you call the hospital
and ask them?
What condition Miyano-san's mother is in.
And how is that related to this?
There's just one truth.
However...
Just the truth doesn't make justice.
Until I find out, I can't tell you.
All right.
This is Sato of the MPD Investigation Unit One.
The ambulance you accepted a little while ago...
Miyano-san, can you understand me?
Blood pressure at 120 over 80.
Please check the x-ray.
Her test results are in. If you would please.
Miyano-san, I need to talk to you.
"Beika General Hospital"
You noticed, didn't you?
Yes.
Then why did you keep quiet about it?
Because truth and justice
aren't necessarily the same.
Please tell me in detail about her
previous respiratory accident.
It was a day of heavy rains.
Apparently as the rain struck it...
...that caused a short-circuit
and the circuit breaker to flip.
Without electricity,
her artificial respirator would stop.
And when it stopped, my mother would die.
At that time I called an electrician's store
and the fire department...
...and somehow got by.
The emergency battery had failed, huh?
I had ordered a new one for it, but it hadn't...
You've already been nursing her
for quite a long time, haven't you?
Since the traffic accident...
It's been 7 years.
It's been very tough on you, hasn't it?
Mom and I didn't get along...
...so when she could still talk,
she told me this.
"I'm just so much baggage, aren't I?" she said.
"Marry whoever you want!"
There was someone who had
promised to marry me.
But...
I couldn't choose him...
That short-circuit in the electricity.
That's what gave you the hint, wasn't it?
That's true.
If it hadn't been for that...
...this wouldn't have happened.
That day...
...a sudden and dreadful idea
popped into my head.
Just like this...
If the electricity doesn't
come back on just like this...
...I could run away from the pain
of nursing her, I thought.
But you didn't do that.
That was impossible for me.
To allow my mother to die.
And that was when you met that underwear thief.
You couldn't do it yourself.
However, by taking advantage of
that man's habit...
...then on some unknown day,
you put that switch in.
"I'm very sorry!"
"Do you like black?"
"The only ones that have disappeared were black."
"I'm sorry."
Pulling the power cord from
the security camera...
...you attached both electrodes
to a clothespin...
...and then hung a pair of black underwear
between each of the electrodes.
You then took a black thread
you had sewn into the underwear...
...and extended it to
the security camera's power cord.
At the moment the thief stole the underwear...
...the clothespin and power cord
would become detached, causing a short.
When you returned each day...
...you would invariably check to see if
the black underwear was there or not.
That man...
...who loved black underwear so much...
...would steal the underwear...
...and thus end your mother's life...
"Wait, molester!"
"Ala? He's disappeared again."
That's why you could return home
without knowing anything.
But when you saw the underwear was missing,
you understood everything.
"Mom..."
You were thinking your mother
had been killed, weren't you?
Shin'ichi, wait.
Look on the back.
Do you know what the message on
the back of this says?
"It was fun."
"When I get better,
we absolutely have to go again. Yukari!"
Mom...
I think your mother didn't give up living...
...because she wanted to be with you.
I'm sorry...
Forgive me. Mom, I'm sorry.
What about the Helper, Yamashita-san?
Truth is, he became her Helper
due to the guilt he felt...
...from having caused that traffic accident
when he was still a student.
He isn't connected to this case.
I'll surrender to the police.
"Beika General Hospital"
How did it go?
For now it's attempted murder.
Will you arrest her?
But, isn't this strange?
Well...
After all, her mother returned
to breathing on her own because of it.
"There are things that can't be
understood by modern medicine..."
"...but I'd like to believe this is a miracle."
"Your mother will surely recover."
Thank you very much...
Thank you very much!
Hey!
Weren't you listening?
The point is, switching from being
an underwear thief to a molester is just wrong!
Because of what you've done, strange things
have happened and things got complex and sad...
...and caused a lot of trouble,
so don't you EVER do this again!
I'm sorry.
I won't do it again!
Say, Kudo-kun.
When did you make the connection between
those black panties and the respirator?
That underwear thief had a burn on his hand.
"Um, I'm sorry, this too."
"This is a burn, isn't it?"
As ever, you see the small details,
like black panties.
I guess black is best... That's wrong!
There's no mistaking it, Kudo-kun.
That is your achievement!
You're ganging up on me! You're wrong, I said!
Shin'ichi, let's go.
Yes, yes, all right.
"After this, Yukari-san was sent to
the Prosecutor's office for attempted murder..."
"...but in the end she wasn't prosecuted."
Mom... I'm sorry.
Shin'ichi!
Hurry with the password!
Ah, I've gotten numb.
"Spontaneous Respiration"
Let's go.
Yes.
Huh?
Ah, a soccer ball!
What is it?
This is...
...a bomb?!
"West High School Student Detective,
Hattori Heiji"
"The Great Detective of East and West
Are Challenged in an Impossible Murder Mystery"
"This Drama is Fictional"